[Music]
and for the final time good evening and
welcome to Edinburgh
hosting the diving events at the Glasgow
2014 20th Commonwealth Games big wave it
must cost a bit scary but everyone seems
to like it so maybe I'm out of kilter on
this up as we prepare for two more
finals the two last finals of the week
at the Royal Conwell pool I'm actually
by the time we get underway so if I time
we get to the 10-meter later all the
seats will be taken there will be a
raucous atmosphere in here then Jesus
fought three Englishmen in the men's
10-meter three English women and one
Scots woman in the 3-meter springboard
to come up next in their interesting
week always gone to plan not always gone
to the script
but we have 12 to go in the women's
3-meter springboard final we have 11 to
go in the men's 10 metre platform final
alongside me as ever to cast his eye and
give us the intricacies of every dive
and whether it's good bad or indifferent
is the happens 2004 10 metre platform
with synchro silver medalist Leon Taylor
at this point I always ask you that
rather inane question would you do with
so brilliantly what are you expecting
well I'm expecting some diving and I
would like to see some high-class
world-class diving here at the
Commonwealth Games
we saw where as we usually see in the
prelims we see a mixed bag and some
athletes on their game others still to
find theirs and of course quite a spread
through the marks there we are the
crowds warming up and
grace weed going in the women's 3 meter
final she dives in number 3 just 18
years old her second Commonwealth Games
and when she takes to the board the
crowd certainly show their support the
atmosphere is great you can see the
shots of the well that essentially the
diving board and that is the board that
they're going to be diving up that's a
close up at the end of the 3-meter
springboard it's yeah complicated
technical any timing coordination
strength power agility and that's just
to do the very basic of dives and as
we've seen over the last couple of days
a decent hurdle step helps yeah heard of
step is the approach to the end of the
diving board on some of the dives so a
forward and the reverse normally need a
hurdle step that's where you walk down
the diving board she pushed the diving
board down with one foot and then you
leap onto the end of the diving board
not over the end but the end of the
diving board ideally with two feet
usually the best shot best shot at
performing of the dive and what we're
going to be seeing is five dives
performed by each of the ladies five
different groups of dives and here is
the start list so Chum will go first the
first of the English divers Rebecca
Gallen tree up second think grace Reed
for a huge cheer when they come out on
pool deck for her yes you will get a
massive reception and last to go looking
for a notable double here after winning
the 1 meter Jennifer Abel watch out for
mass and Keaney has a chin
more medals for Australia best placed
after the prelims of the English divers
was Hannah Starling precursor to what's
going to happen later with the 10-meter
platform which was force leon's events
they've been to Italy and synchro wise
and on paper it's very easy to say well
it's Tom Daley against Matthew Mitchell
isn't it the Olympic bronze medalist of
2012 against the Olympic gold medalist
of 2008 bit more to it than that yeah
maybe I still think he's going to be a
head head though so yeah there will be a
fight for the bronze I'm sure but I'm
yeah I'm gonna tip yeah we've got some
v8 VIPs in the crowd tonight as you can
see welcome one and all these were the
golden tickets sold out within a matter
of minutes
I think because of the number of seats
still many people to take their seats
but it is very very warm I can assure
you I'm sitting here on my shorts and my
flip-flops and I'm still very warm pick
up the girls that you don't need for the
buckets baby but think we would bring it
anyway three meter individual for the
women will excuse them one by one
mention three English divers one from
Scotland
[Applause]
- from relays ESP from bellezza stream
Australia Britain Canada
first up surely you're good Oh Malaysia
there's Rebecca gone through the first
they will see of the English divers mom
Lisa V reads as grace read loving this
this is a phone call long home support
born in Edinburgh training in Edinburgh
what do they say about Pamela where
they've made every look quite sure I
think I'll smooth will go next then the
devil to Sally or Malaysia please here
black up next in position seven and
[Music]
eight Alice darling forth after the
prelims this morning message in
we'll go to from the ends bouncing kini
gets it right
to put pressure on that winner for this
morning the best prom this morning in
verse Genevieve all of Canada
that's our one to twelve in the dye
border remember five rounds for the win
will be six rounds for the men when we
get to the 10-meter platform almost
immediately afterwards and Jennifer ball
going for a notable double here silver
medalists four years ago
gonna go one better in Delhi I'm from
Delhi to here
just joking physician
yeah royalty in tonight there will be a
lot of dignitaries from various
political parties in tonight as well
it's the hottest ticket in town even
hotter than some of the Edinburgh
Festival tickets which is just getting
underway in the city goes on right the
way through until the end to town so
it's move an overlap beer come while
diving and the Edra festival which might
be why the pubs and bars were rather
busy last night
[Applause]
[Music]
helping John each thank you very much
indeed as we introduce the judges for
the women's 3-meter springboard and here
they are and Elysium our would come with
Chong Valerie pedo Marco for that so and
probably boys the former Canadian diver
now judge will go number six the fate of
the twelve divers to come it's very much
in their hands see how they interpret
the dimes we'll have five rounds of
dives there'll be a lot of similar ones
like for example Shawn Jonas Young who
goes first
will do the inward two-and-a-half
somersaults dive will also be performed
a slightly different way by grace Reed
and then by Annabel Smith
temperature Sabri and yang ye and a
starling esta chin and Jennifer Abel so
pretty much half or more than half all
the divers will go for in technical temp
school of 405 B translates into an
inward two and a half somersault so they
go in reverse order so 12 place finish
goes first the best of the morning will
go last and that's Jennifer a board
who's going for a notable double here so
the advantage of diving last is that the
judges tend to expect the best dives to
come at the last bit of the round
because you were the winner of the
delivery so the momentum of the
competition can often carry the higher
marks being awarded to the divers at the
back end of the field but it doesn't
always go that way but sometimes it does
here we go competition is underway
referee's whistle blowing so we have our
first diver on the board highest Yong
jun-hyung of Malaysia with an A with two
and a half so a source
well Cheung would have been looking for
a stronger star than that leaving the
dive short of vertical takeoff looked
okay it's a difficult dive to do so you
need to squeeze into that pipe shake
which he does just let it go her legs a
little bit too early
leaving the dive marginally short of
verticals let's see what she gets if
you're looking for sevens really and 6.5
is what she gets so kind of mid-range
really seven and above very good six
half and below not quite so good against
six and a half since six is twenty not
doing challenging for the upper echelon
of this event we took it down to be much
further down quality normally shows that
was the morning that could be parked and
will start all over again with a forward
two and a half seven sorts one twist for
Rebecca to roll over as she goes into
the water she's back from the end on the
take-off which means yes to shift her
weight forward in order to complete the
dive and that affects the entry so she
rolls over vertical only scoffs I think
bother than eight which would have been
ideal opening yeah
57 it is six Justin white gets the seven
she wanted or above six and to 6.5 takes
a second for typing it's
- great grace grace read on the board
now she's doing a slightly different
version of the in with two and a half
somersaults this one were tuck not with
pike consequently it's not worth three
point zero it's worth 2.7 it's kind of
where her program to take she is at the
moment well that's a beautiful opening
round I'd once again from grace and spot
mention opting for the slightly easier
inward so this is the top position
bending at the hips under the knees
grabbing hold of the shins squeezing
tight straight up and I've lowered the
groove difficulties that would see her
possibly at the bottom of the
leaderboard so far however another
consistent dive from grace how people
have fought wrong say they degree of
difficulty nowhere near as high as it
needs to be to change for the medals
unless everybody drops off but ta do
what she's capable of doing at this
stage and she's doing it very well 56.7
keeps her in the mix Pamela we're 21
years of age wrong candidate just to
diving by a dad
ice hockey oh that ice cream bet it was
Bob beautiful opening band I fabulous
entry into the water this is where the
marks are awarded the take off his goods
Pike shape could do with squeeze get a
little tighter little bit of an arch as
she goes in and that should see her top
of the leaderboard so far only four
divers in this final so far bronze
medalist of the 2013 World Championships
in Barcelona
although she has a pedigree to make a
way through safe further down the
standings and we thought she would be
the swine balancer can easy be
reversible has been in quality
competitions this week shaky start
warranted Annabel Smith she would like
to rectify all that start all over again
with her inward two and a half summer
sorts of pike you know this dive by now
and they will see it several more times
three point zero degree of difficulty
for her
well that's a little bit better than
this morning on a takeoff she was
backing away from the diving board a
little bit too much which can affect the
rotation but she manages to get after it
driving those hips up and over ducking
her chin slightly as she moves past
vertical into the water server should
get her over 60 points 63 to be precise
and easy calculation to make 777 will
all count towards total multiply that by
the degree of difficulty gives you 63
opening dive just in mine and where in
terms of the standings great early days
yet by Browns and some bigger dive still
to come nepeta every oh Malaysia
once again the inward two and a half
nice house very impressed with this
young 15 year old she has sometimes they
turn in a list which she tends to
struggle a little bit more with but this
was a corking opening in the prelims
she's just allowed that to go over as
she's entered the water so it won't be
quite as impressive as it was earlier
still she'll be one to watch and only
1563 put right alongside Annabel smith
seen by the judges as precisely same
dive in terms of quality
Alysia black goes for something
different
this will be again 3.0 type so the
degree of difficulty the same but this
is a Ford two and a half somersaults
with one twist for the second of the
English divers will see in the bull side
with her coach Edwin knows she's
actually feeling under the weather but
you would tell from that maybe something
she's eaten or anything so she's really
struggling with her energy so this is
going to be a long start long
competition for but look at that to kick
off with 17.5 well whatever she's done
something has worked Michigan asleep
feeling a bit restored and refreshed
17.5 0
nice job by Alisha flag
and Lee from Malaysia up next and we're
back to the N word two and a half again
best we've seen so far those Pamela
where and Sabri and Smith they see a
black boat first to go over 70 in this
first round
very very nice well executed it's a
compare and contrast this that you've
returned half in the pike position this
will get over 65 points I think
finishing higher keeping the splashdown
than her teammate just two before her
Sudbury this is the slightly older more
experienced gangee and she have you
strapped on a tricep which is no comment
goes into second place by Delicia black
[Music]
on to darling you will have a big smile
see the mode go I'll receive it when we
go front Tom smile is out just disappear
that she gets her game face on it gets
ready to start the inward two and a half
seven sauce the best based off the
English this morning but of course the
points do not get carried forward 3.0 to
remind you in word to an hour
somersaults oh good very good from the
hand out
this morning she just probably like a
lot of the girls a little bit tired
short water enemy is there ever she
comes up this is a really strong attacks
to take off squeeze into that Pike shape
yeah it's straight up and down probably
a little bit low on the water for more
than a seven but we shall see how we'll
find out now three sevens 63 joint
fourth but the group of sixty threes
coming together three more to go three
best divers from this morning
up next mr. Jin these diver were to
Sydney in the year 2009 she will also be
doing the diver you've seen a lot of all
around the car 63 to 67 mark so far she
better that no I think he is a little
short at vertical to better that she
will be around about 60 points takeoff
is okay but she backs away from the time
you bought a little bit too much which
leaves her sure to vertical as she goes
into the water
the judges will penalize kids will be
further down the leaderboard
yeah 61.5 so six and a half and sevens
4s to chin of that 3.0 dive
now on to the new zealand-born and now
australians and medicine kini she is
certainly one to watch here she was on
the one so she is in a three not quite
so expensive on the three sounds what
she can do
back two and a half seven salts with
Pike 3.0 for the Australian or just
washing over that she goes into the
water back two and a half somersaults in
the pike position all of the girls will
use a back two and a half most of them
in the pike position the difference
here's Madison jumps through the roof
she is so powerful only 18 years old
credible job wasn't wattmeter she really
does set herself apart letting a fault
on the entry causes the marks to be low
63 which matches what Starling Smith
Sabri and now key me on 63 this is the
class act of the field in terms of what
she's done in the past of what she did
this morning silver medal from Delhi
already got the 1 meter title under her
belt system affable with her inward two
and a half somersaults yep she's 74
years ago the gold medal last night in
the 1 meter springboard and here she is
on her favorite three meter top
qualifier ready to open up her campaign
its steady steadfast where she's out
this evening
Church 5 didn't like you very much but
sevens and a 7.5 for Jennifer and of the
first round of five off the 3-meter
springboard for women that's how it
looks police see a black at the top only
person to go over 70 in the first minute
lovely start and an ye and second place
a couple of Canadians tied for third and
grace read that you just have a lower
degree of difficulty for a majority of a
program so I expect you to keep up with
the more established performers but you
get middle of the time they'll be a
great achievement round 2 of the 3-meter
springboard for women young young smoke
it in 12th place we could get rid of 2
this morning but she got in in 12 for
the for three and a half yet little bit
of difficulty with this in training so
what's this so good in the preliminaries
and she's missed it again in the final
four three and a half in the tuck
position but Nick at the knees bending
at the hips in the Tuck shape just
holding on to that touchy a fraction too
long
over rotating listener a change so all
in all know that great but 6.5 it's an
okay return for Sean John Young of
Malaysia
fifty four point six zero for that the
gallantry gold with Elise here black in
the three metre synchro made a senior
debut 10 years ago for Great Britain she
is for England there's a reverse two and
a half somersaults with Mike yes that's
a good dive from from Becky this is the
one that sometimes can get away from her
she has a tendency to pull the dive over
this time she waits let's go at the
correct time little bit of a back arch a
little bit of an overvote ation so she
probably won't get more than a 7 which
is a shame because the height on that
time is excellent
Oh ticket they took the cameraman out
there I'm doing my son bullshit that's
more importantly the cameraman took care
out there Rebecca captain streaky grace
read smile when she got onto the board
no it's a studied concentration 2.8 on
this one
yes we're tuck and rather with pike
forward three and a half somersaults for
all these Scots
she is just rising to the occasion low
on the degree of difficulty yes but high
on the consistency unfaltering under the
expectation of this home cried in a home
pool home country and she certainly
takes that forward three and a half on
and there's a great job she just Simmons
never shabby and 58.8 walk with her
right alongside Rebecca gallantry at the
moment should be another one of our
emerging divers for a future Pamela
where not only third that's where she
fish at bass load of the world champs
last year for three and a half for her
[Music]
well she's got a point to prove she's
coming out in attacking every one of
these dives not holding back at all see
example you really need to get after
this it's 3.12 griffith going for a
reason it's difficult you need the high
if you get invited yet sevens you're
gonna get mid-60s 65 66 and that's what
she'll be looking for exactly 60 5.10
gonna face so maybe she expected more
either from the judges or might be of
herself there but
that's just a game face your game face
yeah I know well there you go
yeah you probably played rose on point
did she flee shit Annabel Smith where
they reverse two and a half some resorts
with Mike 3.0 for the Australian well
leaving the dive short vertical there
went Bob on the takeoff if you listen
carefully you might be up to here on the
replay obviously but she stamps the
diving board she's not on the end so
there's a missed coordination with a
diving board did that I being board is
your friend you need to t treat it
nicely so go down with it and then it'll
fling you up in the air if you stamp it
it'll flick you off that's what happened
to Annabel yeah really
you pay a little pay for those channels
5.5 s cross aboard 49.5 Annabel Smith
damnit ah Sabri for Malaysia goes with
the fourth three and a half somersaults
with Mike currently in fifth place it's
a good dive this is her favorite
movements the forward and the inward
that she opened up with in the first
round little bit back from the end of
the time you bots are making it hard
work but she does hang on just about
long enough to get it in so this was
good in the prelims not quite as good in
the same quality because of the falter
on the takeoff so maybe the 15-yard for
Malaysia will start to slip away now as
she moves towards the weaker part of her
program and she didn't lead at one stage
this morning but not gonna be leaving
here 55.8 0 not a great return on that
dive for Dara Tysabri now Elise you're
black cause our current leader only
person in the first round to go over 70
points
now wouldn't be nice she kept backing
that up with her back two and a half
somersaults 3.0 needs 60 though be in
front panel aware now we know that she
is more than capable of getting 60 on
this dive
so those soft in her body she went into
the water arching through the back so
swinging the arms take off looks okay I
did mention in mind one that she isn't
very well now she looked a little weak
on the takeoff they're a little soft on
the way out to dive look like hard works
so I'm hoping she's got enough energy
for the next three dives rubbing your
eyes yeah so it's tough to put yourself
through that I should look at all well
does she its second the time being I'll
be back ping Yin Yi of Malaysia me right
- she was off the first round with the
DC of black bleeding yes her for three
and a half worth three point one in the
pike position so a high tariff dive for
her everyone executed as well Lasky
effort
from the old of elysian you need 21 is 3
in the final young opening up she's the
first diver this is one of her hardest
dives or the hardest dive by way of
degree of difficulty 3.1 she's done a
good job they'll be high 60s and she
goes into the lead hello quite 70 but
very closer 60 8.20 she does go into
Libra 7.5 and 7s and Hannah Starling and
Esther chin who will follow her we'll
all be going with the same dive so we
were to move difficulty just up the
notch to 3.1 just preparing yourself for
her for three and a half somersaults
currently in fifth place 72 will take
her into the lead boy it's very good
I'm not sure whether that would be good
enough to get over 70 points it is three
point one degree of difficulty she does
go up up and away
hichy into the water it's a little bit
low she ends up short but then ducks
ahead and ends up going over so this
judges Mike penalized quite heavily for
that let's wait and see
yeah I think that I will say taking the
mark off six point five six point five
and six point five will count remember
those marks would light through them do
not count the overall score at sixty
point four five is what she receives for
that third place now now the big three
from this morning that's the chin up
first same dive once again you'll see
something different from Madison Keaney
after this whoa what a beauty an
absolute beauty Esther slightly further
down after her first round dive that we
would expect now this will rocket us
straight up the leaderboard three point
one we've seen it before if it gets
close to 70 points or over 70 points
she's gonna leapfrog a few of her fellow
competitors and she does yes she has
done just that sixteen nine point seven
five three seven point five and
it's Malaysia 1 Australia to where the
Hang en Yi in first place
Madison kini of Australia now this is a
lot of Dyson takes time she has a little
problem with 63 she got in the first
round reverse two and a half somersaults
with pike second time round oh she does
so well hurdle step was a little bit off
she's leaning so that's the approach to
the end she's leaning too far forward
she's right on the corner of the board
but look at the height she gets you must
be able to see that at home it is
incredible especially that she's corner
boarding which is so he landed the
corner with a board it's not very easy
to do anything from there let alone a
reverse two and a half in the pike
position and she managed to get seven
and a half's on it Wow she was virtually
up in that Glasgow logo by there that's
how high she went seven point five
across the board 67.5 and the moment she
is in their place for that may well
changed her change is likely to change
with Jennifer table up next the one
meter champion always keeps her game
face on a game head on for the evening
looked very good this morning so that's
a worry for everybody else back two and
a half somersaults with Mike to finish
round two of the 3-meter springboard
yeah nice very nice indeed from Jennifer
golde last night will it be gold again
tonight so far it looks as though she is
very much in the hunt for another gold
medal just allowing the dive to tip over
slightly vertical so I think it might
get 8 kept the splash down nicely couple
of eights and a 7.5 and not quite in the
Li the mome but very very close to it
very tight the tops you'll see in a
moment we reveal the leaderboard at the
end of round 2 which looks like this and
yet ye of Malaysia first stable than the
two Australians for the English diver on
the front page - murmurs Hannah Starling
in sick then Elysia flag and Annabel
Smith just to the moment cast adrift but
at the bottom of the pile grace Reed for
Scotland in 9th along with Rebekah
gallantry young of Malaysia is currently
ranked 11th and she is opted to go
because the choice is the divers in
which order they take these dives for a
back to earn our somersaults with Viking
so we don't my Annabel Smith like all
the other divers in this round
well she looks CISO cheese a little bit
well I'm not sure a little bit tired not
quite got a competition head on she is
much much better than this
she only just qualified for this final
we lost two ladies this morning in the
prelims and expect much better function
she is a better diver than this still
good yeah yeah when she gets her bike
she can really really get it right yes
you know absolutely outstanding dives in
the first four days here that wasn't one
of them but wasn't too bad
three sevens Rebecca Gallen teri joint
night after the second round this one
will be a 4-3 and our summer sorts with
Pike war the City of Leeds diver
terrific tie fun packing
gold medal in the three metre synchro
Delicia blag good for three and a half
feet of pike position punching a hole in
the water by grabbing the hands she goes
in you see the sprays on the surface of
the water there that's so worth
mentioning that's to disturb the surface
of the water so the divers know exactly
where the surface is because if there
are no sprays no agitation all the
surface of the water all the divers can
see is the bottom of the pool so just
that little bit of spray gives you an
exact idea where the surface is so when
you grab your hands just before going in
you know where it is you have you've
asked that question and Leon has
answered it for you Greece reads for two
and a half somersaults one twist for the
Scottish diver 3.0 one of her bigger
tariffs beautiful dive for two and a
half one twist 3.0 lots going on I'm
gonna get the rotation into the
one-and-a-half somersaults there's the
one twist then complete the extra
somersault to make it two and a half
somersaults Gracie's best dive offer
programs so far we'll get 62 63 any
advance no we're staying on 63 three
sevens good nice and solid
on 78 points already for her say don't
expect metal from grace it will be far
too much to expect with the degree of
difficulty she's got but looking for a
middle-of-the-pack finish if she can
achieve it and we're now for Canada and
we're two and a half fifth
or faltering she came out all guns
blazing first two bands put herself in
the business end of the field was thing
in fifth after the second man that will
see her drop from the leaderboard not
getting enough rotation ended up shorter
vertical as she goes in weren't
mentioning us watching the replays here
the judges did not see the slo-moes they
do not see the replay they input their
scores immediately as soon as the divers
hit the wall to the judges to require to
put their scores in and they're not
allowed to look at each other's scores
or ask each other or confer they as
little dividers could you see yeah a
shot where they're divided from each
other so I'm copying somebody else's
homework isn't that okay not allowed to
peek over to go what do you think of
that one oh six 6.5 Annabel Smith has a
back two and a half somersaults to
perform now for us 3.0 for the
Australian
that's where the Fon Smith she was right
down at the bottom of the leaderboard
after a poor second man died she will
now pick yourself back up with that when
they back two and a half in the pike
position as we look through the replay
there you can see the strain going
through the body pulling the top of the
half of the body onto the bottom half to
show the pike shape and then next in the
dyed to land on her head pretty much
vertically looks pretty much like she
was doing this morning not quite where
she needs to be not quite on Form just a
little way off her favorite face and
favorite place to point eight so we're
down in the slightly lower tariff dives
for the Malaysian that was her Sabri
there's no Sun a tough position lot Mike
back two and half so I thought with tuck
so I took one eight office yeah that's
okay for supper as I mentioned her first
two opening main dives a higher degree
of difficulty there in the pike position
now she struggles with this particular
movement the back and the next one that
she's doing is to reverse so she's
opting for the easier degree of
difficulty the 2.8 and tuck position
spinning in a tuck position is easier
than spinning in a pike position just
agreed landing okay on that one is she
yeah she's quite pleased not sure
guess I'll little inclination of the
head to look back at the coach what's
the coach think coaches are never
satisfied or something wrong if you get
a tent or something wrong did he see a
black very listen stop see what she can
carry it on now
would three and a half they know she's
not being on top of her game but I see
what the for three and a half will bring
for her yeah so she isn't feeling top of
the game but that is around about the
top of her game on this dive even though
she's landed right on the corner of the
board she waits wait she's so so strong
[Music]
great dive for Melissa he'll get over 70
points if it does she'll go to the top
of the leaderboard once again and that's
where she was at the end of round one
won't be there at the end of round three
I don't think but seventy one point
three foot sit there temporarily
fourteen points above Rebecca Gallen
tree but here is our current leader hang
in ye of Malaysia it's the back two and
a half four more time and we'll see this
from not from how the sign but that's a
chin starting here something a little
bit different to come up next but here
is our current leader needs fifty nine
to retain that position Oh
faltering Yangyi over she goes
take off looked okay so generating
enough spin speed moving the arms
squeeze to get to the Pike shape and
then just reach you back a little bit
too aggressively tipping over that's
going to get mid-range so maybe five 5.5
s for the judges that will see her less
than 50 points and yeah mm just one dive
like that can scupper your middle
chances and though she's in second place
right now there are four more still to
come in this round she might find
herself in quite a plunge Anna Starling
smile looks at the crowd gets herself
ready focus on what's uni still chat to
herself reverse two and a half
somersaults with Pike Hannah nice really
nice marvelous died from had a little
bit of a skip on the take-off moving
herself Baltimore's the middle of the
pool but she did have one of her feet
over the end of the diving board which
caused that she squares it up nicely she
gets Evans that's a very good third
right dive to the 19 year old from
England punching up they are in the
positions just behind the medals so we
see some faltering here and I won't be
in the top three at the end of this
round but she's not too far away with
our 63 three sevens ester chin 20 year
old a fair share of injury problems
along the way I take a whole year out
with ankle problems not so long ago into
America in 2009 silver in the University
Games last year she is were they back
two and a half somersaults
ah that is the died of her programs so
far we're looking for a vertical entry
with no splash and that is exactly what
we got from Esther chin on this die we
could see the first type scoring above
8.5 that's straight up and down if the
judges are awake and they're in a good
mood it's like you can go higher
that's an eight point five all the way
for me and it is for the judges as well
they have the same view of that as we do
from the commentary box 80.5 Spicer chin
and the Chinese born Australian goes
into the lead by 13 points from Alisha
black but the big movers and shakers are
about to take to the board though just
count me out of medal position is
Madison Keaney of Australia she want to
do something about that the 18 year old
little problem with this third dive oh
did she hit the diving board now I'm
watching it on the screen I wasn't sure
whether she's hit the diving board let's
have a look on the replay I think she
does so she's that high she's right over
the diver donk there you go she hits her
feet on the diving board so the judges
will quite clearly penalize that now
that is a shame because she's so high
it's good palette she just needed to
move the dive a little bit further back
she hits the feet on double world if
it's deemed dangerous judge number one
thought no you hit the board I'm giving
you one point five the rest of the
judges choosing fours and four point
five that could be Madison kini
I think the medals and that would be a
real shame yeah she's got a lot of
talent doesn't always put it all
together at the right time it's Lanie
however it's a complete reverse of that
for two and a half one twist
unfazed by the diver before her hitting
her feet on the diving board Jen is in
the zone focusing on what she can do
what she needs to do one dive at a time
that's how you win the couple of games
and are we looking at the eventual
champion once again one meter last night
midway through just over the three meter
and now clear in the top two with the
Australian ester chin that's how it
stands and elysia Black has moved into
the top three again she was one step
down a bit but she's found perform in
round three and she and Hannah Starling
are in three and four
Esther chin a great time in round three
let's put herself in position hey
Rebecca gantry on the front page so
three English their grace reads moved up
to seven and it looks like a big long
haul back for mass and Keaney and
Annabel Smith if they're gonna challenge
for the medals still mathematically
possible because one to 11 separated by
just 35 points so they just it's quite a
lot but a massive difference for them
reversed two and a half for Shaun yeah
it's definitely up again this was a real
beauty in the prelims he got nines well
I thought she should have got nines I
think they gave her 8.5 one judge gave
her a nine and she's done a lot of
competing over these past few days this
is day number four the diving here Joe's
been on pretty much every day she's
starting to show fatigue seeing a facial
expression there that she's kind of
toughing it out
do you worry about for the cameraman in
your face because every diver when they
come out of the pool good bad or
indifferent as that camera right in
their face you don't wanna smack them at
some point no I didn't even notice it
just focused on what you do
Rebecca gallantry in word two and a half
somersaults with tuck in this is down in
the 2.7 range so consequently means this
has to be very good if she's to retain
her sixth position or push a bit further
up the table and for for the diver
originally from Essex what a shame she's
opting for the easier in word so in the
Tuck position you get less to group
difficulty just two point seven and then
creams this really worked for Becky here
the takeoff is good the exit is okay and
then she just lets it over rotate baby
needs to exit the dive a little bit
sooner to ensure the vertical entry
[Music]
watching the B play and you get the
feedback from a coach ad Hinchcliffe
saying good start just needs to lighten
up around the sides 6s yeah less than
fifty for her Chris reads granddad to
the exhibition diving the parents
weren't involved in diving at all but
that's not Pamela where by the way that
is definitely grace read on the board
with a reverse two and a half
somersaults with tuck well done grace
I'm laughing because he's just raised a
cane so consistent she knows she's like
any degree of difficulty
he's matching many of the athletes died
for dive with execution this will get a
handful of sevens yes she'll be here
maybe close to sixty points with that
judge one seniors at seven point five a
couple of seven point five s discarded
as are a couple of sevens to that 60
point two zero low tariff dive very big
dive in terms of execution and we're
ain't place at the moment for Canaan but
that's makeable in terms of the bridging
the gap reverse two and a half again
yeah that's gonna help that's certainly
gonna help fabulous dive off the back of
her and very average inward two and a
half in the pike position this is the
reverse two and a half she reaches time
just allowing the dive to tip opens tip
open
excuse me tip over it's been a long day
for me as well very warm in this balls
it's not making up words in a minute you
never know oh you know what you do that
anyway
three sevens sixty-three
Leon Taylor give you the full lowdown or
take on that and grace Reid and Pamela
we're very close together now 244 the
Canadian 238 or grace Reid and the Bill
Smith forward three and a half
samasource with Mike 3.1 biggest I've
certainly is
she needed a really good take up on that
so in order to get the best take off you
need to land right on the end of the
diving board she's just a little bit
back from the end so has to squeeze into
that pike check darker chin in as she
enters the water in order to get to the
close to vertical as possible when she
does a reasonable job on in mind where
and read she parks herself which means
in terms of mills she's a long way shy
of that no Sudbury very very good this
morning say she led at one stage but
she's at the other end of the pack this
time here comes her 2.8 different
tariffs on this verse two and a half a
somersault she's nailed it
yes much better reverse turn half in the
Tuck position it's only 2.8 depictive
good if you were to do it in the pike
position it's 3.0 summary the 15-year
old for malaysia here performing this
dive to the very best of our ability and
be watching this in training it's one of
her dies a bogey dies potentially and
that is very good
eight and seven point five so the top
three currently are separated by two
points and we're double to separate and
grace Reed 240 plays 239 and 238
we see a black sky self back in the
third place not feeling well at all
first round diamond third round dive
were exemplary our good would be to see
a do a brilliant reverse two and a half
somersaults with pike in round four
well it was almost brilliant almost
brilliant beautiful take off the disses
from the diving board squeezing into the
Pike shape slight bending and he said
the judges won't see that she just
reached back a little bit with a little
bit too much effort causing the time to
go over she'd done all the hard work and
just faltered on the entry she's good
enough to put her in the lead for now
248 3054 but she'll be happy when this
competition is over let's get back in a
bit get some sleep Europeans are coming
soon couple of weeks time for her so the
other British competitors here Hank
Yin Yi of Malaysia yes place so this
reverse two-and-a-half is good she could
put pressure on the likes of Abel and
chin there's only one more round after
this this has to be good
yes that's good from Yangyi reverse turn
half in the pike position she faltered
previously on the third round dive it's
an okay take off a little bit scruffy
into the pike shape she could get sevens
on this will hold her wherever she was
at the end of last round which I think
was in fifth it's putting pressure to
making sure they have to hit their dives
at least you're black still in position
a though it's things down with four to
come in this round I can't finish any
worse than fifth and one place above
that in fourth after round three was
Alice darling
for England nineteen year old from Leeds
originally a swimmer I swear just before
a ninth birthday dad I mean look she's
very glad she did back two and a half
somersaults with Pike 3.0 for Hannah yes
very nice sneaks that dive in
beautifully little bit lower than water
the take-off is good but she's not
finishing the dive high enough in order
to get the drop to get more than seven
she does a very nice job of fitting that
in I think close to alyssia's score so
far she goes to number one only by mana
mark at one point between our Starling
and Alicia plaque in second but smile
returns to the base they were far away
from that face to be honest he's not
current leader marginally in front of
Jennifer Abel I think she would have a
distance between herself and the
Canadian with her reverse two and a half
oh she was in the lead before and now
she's gonna be difficult to beat the
Australians cheering and so they should
beautiful die from Esther chin reverse
two and a half at the pike position
drills that entry could be eight point
five maybe even a nine if it is she's
gonna go 75 and then she's gonna be
difficult it's a catch just what he
dived to go for Esther chin two divers
in this round 76 54
Esther Jen 8.5 course the board so
that's a big margin that she's open up
on the rest nobody in the to 80 range
embryos in the two 40s so Madsen Keaney
I think their last dive is done for her
chances of a medal it's a for three and
a half now you've got to give credit to
this young lady she's only 18 and she is
a super talent she has got so much
potential
we're Lance just on the end of the
diving pool but look how high above the
five meter board in the background she
goes that's a beautiful dive 68 poison
that will squeeze the gap she'll only be
ten points off of mental now it's up too
far let's wait and see what happens
it'll be down to the exciting last round
Esther chin goes to 84 where this mess
and Keaney go to 39.2 there's 10 points
behind have a starling 9 mind Alyssia
black
the moment house darling is in a middle
position
Jennifer avol knows that she has to be
top of her game now the catch has to
chip with her for three and a half oh
well she does need to be top of a game
in that is not top of her game she will
go into the silver medal position at the
moment with one man to go this is three
point one she would have needed eights
to catch Esther chin that is less than
eight the chair centering the water
still in a slight Pike position throwing
up a bit of splash coming towards us
she's gonna be left points to make up in
round number five if she wants to get
the gold and she doesn't want to do the
double here does Jennifer but at the
moment she was sold methods four years
ago
that's where she's heading in 2014 as
the chin to 84 look at that and a
starling and Alicia black battling it
out for the bronze at the moment thank
ye in fifth and Pam we're at 6 then the
rest with grace Reed in there in 9th
place so this hopefully look it's for we
go into the round well the degree of
difficulties looking like for the
English divers here yes so let's see a
black is down on DD 2.7 so it's gonna be
difficult for her Hannah Starling is a
3.0 Esther chin 3.0 my does Cikini 3.0
jennifer April 3.0 Oh game on Oh
certainly is Chung Jong hyung are
Malaysia her last dive 2.9 on this one
no choke very much off her game this
evening what a shame because when she's
diving well she's that did like to watch
this evening tough day at the office
finishing up here with a very average
dive to go with a very average list of
dies what a shame because she is a
beautiful diver and we haven't seen the
best of her this evening 5.5 s I saw
those some people to make you a night of
it they've actually got the beers in and
the drinks in and they're watching us
tonight they've set their Saturday night
aside for
Leon and Bob who said having Leon
Saturday night it's heavy out here and
sir it's like harking back to the winter
for the fire Rob put your slippers off
Rebecca Gallen tree it's not gonna be a
metal day for her today that she may
well finish where she started in terms
of the dye border in 11th place that's
where she is right now back two and a
half sour sauce with pike for Becky to
finish off with it's worth three point
zero God she sneaks out it within I see
just a little bit aggressive as she goes
into the water the divers pretty much
know when they hit the water whether
it's good or not you get a feeling
through your body bit of a shock wave
baby and think you would have felt the
water hit on his shins and ankles she's
got instance she knows that she won't be
coming up to AIDS but she definitely
better than four so sevens coming her
way
sevens is exactly and precisely what you
get 63 for Becky gallantry 292 20 grace
read last tide biggest cheer of the
night for her she has performs
impeccably all the way through it's a
low tariff time to finish with but it's
the quality of the diving which has been
so impressive from grace these was from
James Heatley when he was diving in the
men's event back two and a half
somersault with tuck for her must die
for Scotland's grace Reed does she
finishes off in style a little bit too
much splash being thrown up
she has done so well in the one meeting
yesterday prelims and finals and today
in the 3-meter prelims and finals so
coach jenny lehmann will be thrilled
so are the crowd so will her parents be
here we're both here to watch her great
dive good finish and what a wonderful
couple games her second would you
believe at the age of 18 nearly 300
nearly 300 she would love to have been
there well she's not too far shy and
sure a barrier to got a picture of the
score wall was currently shows her in
first place she's not gonna finish there
she's not a fish in the medals but the
time being she is hitting the table and
we're in sixth for two-and-a-half
samasource one twist 3.0 for finishing
off she finishes off with a marvelous
dive 3.0 the forward two and a half one
twist we're gonna see this a lot coming
up there's going to be the consecutive
for two and a half one twist only two
athletes coming up at the next eight
electing not to do this partners
starting it off good steps point fives
yeah nice 60 7.50
she is the first of the divers to go
over 300 300 8.10 would not I don't
think be enough so a quick calculation
hardly like you to be good enough for a
medal today rather disappointing it
Annabel Smith today just quite worked
out for either in the prelims or in the
final type for two and a half with one
twist we mentioned you'll see a lot more
to finish off it's a solid finish for
Manorville Smith
she was intent after the fourth lines
and I think she'll be around about that
place after that as well even though
that's a good dive lots of the girls
finishing on their best dives which
makes sense you want to finish on a good
one this is good from Smith probably
identical scores coming her way as we
saw for the Canadian Pamela just before
her 7.5 s across the board 67 so she
isn't quite get over the rubric another
300 next up it is dammit
Sabri we've seen it mix back from her
today very impressive in parts in the
morning not quite so this evening and
again it is that forward two and a half
so you're able to look and see what you
think along with the judges 3.0 on the
DD our fault we got her last dive as
well it's unfortunate because what 415
she's doing a sterling job isn't she
lots to learn great cover wealth games
lots to take away but no medals and she
will drop down the leaderboard there put
it behind the banker gallantry and grace
Reed at one stage she was ahead of both
45 that's what she's got on that another
great return and there are six more to
go
the 1 2 3 is where Smith and Reed but
knowing any of those are gonna get
medals now they see a black still in
fourth place and still in a position to
challenge but and here's the big but it
is a low tariff dive 2.7 it's a bit like
a Tonya couch on the 10 finishing with a
lower tariff tie but one that she feels
comfortable with and this is an inward
two and a half somersaults with tuck
well she's giving her best shot she
isn't feeling very well this year
shaking hand she comes out she knows too
soon she hit the water
you'll feel parts of your body going
through and if it's smooth it's a ripper
tree if you get hit by the water which
is what alyssa has happened that means
she's throwing up splash she won't get
above sevens on this low degree of
difficulty she will not win a medal what
a shame
hope she feels better soon yeah get well
soon Elise yep she just wants to get
away from here and we get straight to
bed and just recover but good luck
choice she's out I know she's with the
Europeans very shortly so couple of
weeks to recover and get her back in
full check again
ping yang ye off malaysia 5th place so
still got a target of a top-three finish
one more time the three point zero for
two and a half for the next Malaysian
yeah it's good you hear the malaysia
contingent shout and Cheer there they
are yeah they like it and she's done a
very good job they're toast right over
the end of the diving board she manages
to pop the diaper that will put her top
of the leaderboard actually with that
we're still four divers still to come
Wow it's gonna be right down to the wire
this is good stuff she's diving at it's
very best yeah that's close we have no
idea where the medals are going yet not
to she but she might have won with that
300 8.20 at the top she goes yes did you
believe 0.1 of a point ahead of BAM
where that's how close super tight
darling is in third place she does hella
high tariffs dive and elysia black it is
a for two and a half somersaults one
twists like you probably know that by
now come on hammer third place yeah
Suzie can do it I so tremendous die from
understanding will that be enough she's
thrown down the gauntlet to the rest of
them let's wait and see what happens Wow
I am super impressed beautiful type that
so died for the competition that's going
to go over 65 points and that might be
enough for a medal I'll pour my rather
damaged reputation on the line and say
it will be good enough remember I'm sure
sure now with that it's colorful
pressure on everybody else God has to
chain the leader Jennifer able to come
mazzantini between across mass and key
is still mathematically gonna overtake
that at the moment in the more one
position is Hannah Starling with three
hundred sixteen point nine five
interesting stuff now 32 is all as the
chin needs to overtake Hannah on her for
two and a half well I think we could be
looking at the Commonwealth Games
champion right there she had a bit of a
lead Jennifer a ball probably is the
only
can capture as the chair has been
rocking it this evening and that's a
really good dive to finish but it's not
out of Jennifer Abel's reach it's not as
good as Hanna starlings it'll get moving
or mid-60s probably with sevens coming
her way
yeah three four seven is the point to be
and only able could do that and she is
up after Madison Keaney they in 75
although that's maybe seventy six she
needs it's gonna have to be a spot on
the she can make in her last type which
is a different die from everybody else's
that you've seen recently now Madison
kini cannot catch Esther chinch he can
catch Hannah styling with a seventy
seven point seven on this forward to an
are they the under seventy seven Hannah
has a medal oh it's a good tie from the
Australian I do not think that will be
good enough for her to stand on the
podium of course she hit the feet on the
diving board in dramatic fashion so that
means that Hannah Starling will win at
least the bronze at least the bronze
that's good diving from the Australian
she is a super talent but I am
absolutely thrilled for Hannah Starling
I can now confirm or stand on the podium
she will at least on the rung of three
because Esther chin has a middle and a
starling has a medal what color we would
discover in the next minute the scenario
is straightforward it's easy it's simple
it's seventy three point five in other
words kind of eight and a half's really
for Jeff Abel for gold for Canada
no it won't be gold for Canada it's gold
faust raelia that will be I think good
enough for silver she only needs five
5.5 s to ensure the silver it's not very
good it will be very close but I think
it's good enough it's a job dye from the
diffe world of defending champion but
the one meter champion silver medalist
for use we can see her disappointment
silver again for able gold for Australia
as the chin and another medal for
teaming a very Australian celebrating
what a contest great diving for mr. chin
hair Sachin taking the gold Jeff able
with the silver but Hanna Starling who
looked very good this morning has
improved her standard the two hundred
sixteen point nine five she got in the
end good enough for third place
edging out Madison kini Aang and Pamela
where the bronze medalist from last year
and the world championships her well
done has darling a major step forward
for the 19 year old from Leeds but his
bronze for her Canada will Jennifer able
getting a silver to add to her gold in
the one meter but Esther chin looked
very good in the one looking good in
three with the gold
and there's the 7 to 12 only see a blank
in 7 not being at all well we do wish
her well because few magic obedia this
kind of little not feeling at your best
Annabel Smith innate grace Reid
finishing night Rebecca gallantry in
10th we'll leave you with some images of
that woman's 3-meter springboard we're
about half an hour away from the men's
10 metre platform you know what that
means the arrival of daily and on
Matthew Mitchum as well hope you join us
for that I'm sure you will and we will
be on BBC 3 as well you want to watch it
on the big telly 7:30 BBC 3 for the
men's 10 metre platform - well done
Hannah Starling wonder nest chin and
jumper Abel as well with the gold and
silver - nice bonus prods if you like
fairness darling from the under myself
back with you in about 25 minutes
[Applause]
[Music]
three concepts
three dual points
[Music]
[Applause]
drive faster
[Music]
three doing nice
[Applause]
[Music]
the competition
it would
[Music]
No
those dice
[Music]
[Applause]
James
[Music]
[Applause]
with the American division we have
first diver in six rounds of the
10-meter platform four men will bid the
Indian that sit off but there she yeah
it's a four three Niles somersault with
pike is gonna go for Leon and I both
watched quite closely his preparation
for tonight's final little bit concern
for this young man to be honest he
wasn't really getting him any of his
dives right hopefully that's all stored
away
here's his first round I've well sir for
moment to kick this final off big tidal
wave being thrown up there luck by the
young Indian only 17 years old and this
is pretty reflective of what he was
doing the training over he goes get your
surfboard sight surf is up for short
wolf
I cannot say I'm terribly surprised by
that threes and 2.5 s Ginga is build up
to this I think I saw maybe one diver
looked okay bring his bow through point
a testing and troubling build-up now 14
year old matthew dixon from plymouth
great to have him here and great to see
what he can do on this forward three and
a half somersaults with pike 3.0 for the
oh man it's best marks by the way three
ninety eight point two five boys a
little bit short at vertical but he does
get that rip entry bit of a crowd
favorite here and i'm not surprised just
tiny his head there's only chest above
the bars the safety bars up on the ten
meter as you see clearly is he on the
replay the judges of course do not see
the replay yet is award two shorter
vertical so the marks will reflect that
forty nine point five formats wears over
sixty this morning so he said levin
points down on how he started in the
prelims
Chuya we like something other Malaysian
dive has actually been a bit of a mixed
bag this week he's really on it he's
really on it gets big marks he too
starts with a for three and a half
somersaults with Mike 3.0 and well the
divers will do this one to nice from Chu
Yuri looking for that vertical entry
splash this and he gets exactly that
he's a little bit ragged my Julie gets
hit enough like shape eventually for
this
yes form these good he's gonna get
eighths on that which is excellent I've
been watching money's on the dive so he
tends to be a little bit here and there
but that's a solid start
72 for to Yui one of two Malaysians in
the final coach is saying where that can
improve
perhaps we can improve for the remaining
five rounds as well now this man started
like a train this morning is open and
dive the arms and back double somersault
to and I'll twist we're about to see
look very very impressive see we could
do with this one
oh it's nearly as good as the prelim
that's a huge dive to open with he got
massive 91 on this in the prelim he
isn't gonna be far away from that now
this would get mid-80s some ways three
point six degree of difficulty he's
gonna get a little bit too much blast
being thrown up four nines commonly
baked goods opens his campaign very good
dive 86.4 for Dominic bedgood 14 points
player to Yui Matt Dixon with 49.5 third
place currently say does Helen looking
forward to two more English divers to
come James Denny up in a couple and Tom
Daly cuz he was the best qualifier this
morning will go last so here's the thing
yang now museum formerly of China for
three and a half well just letting the
died run away the take off was good
probably a little bit too much forward
momentum she moves away from the diving
board quite considerably
this can make controlling the die a
little bit more challenging comes out
with plenty of time just rolling over
there a little bit of splash being
thrown up so 3.0 relatively low degree
of difficulty compared to some of the
dives in his repertoire and he's a
little bit off the pace 58.5 sticks him
in behind bedgood a strong opening for
the Australian who you saw as we were
joining to Yui in second place
James dedi second of the Englishman
ninth of the Europeans on the 10-meter
board went over 400 points whether they
is the silver medalists on the platform
and the British Championships earlier
this year he will start with a 3.2 nice
opening gambit for James inward three
and a half somersaults with tuck before
the second of three Englishmen and you
know who comes third
but there's a good stuff on James steady
really clean on the water just a little
bit sure this goes in in fact he doesn't
quite straighten out enough take off his
good squeeze into that touching three
and a half somersault pints out has a
good look at the water but you see them
he's got his backside sticking out as he
goes in he won't get more than seven for
that which is a shame because have you
to straighten out completely
he'd have been getting eight maybe even
more 777th on a 3.2 d D we have D D D
here Denny Daly and Dixon
[Music]
goats in yang malaysia already show what
he can do on the 3-meter board by going
on to win it absolutely a few English
hearts not least of all jackal or from
three to ten and quite put in the
performance yet to suggest he's a
medalist but it's a final now not the
prelim since we're reading matters back
two and a half somersaults one and a
half twists in the pike position three
point two yet I'm very well this money
oopsy Liang make one mistake which is
why he's middle at the pack of divers
dive in reverse order from these
standings in the prelim this is good for
me to see like three point two it's
actually a relatively easy twist in
comparison to what you're going to see
Mitchum Daly and Denny try the back two
and a half somersaults two and a half
twist this is a two and a half
somersaults one and a half twist it's
worked out okay for boom the marks we
wait for judges other indecisive or the
technology is letting us down the most
so we can't bring you what he's got as
yet it will be appearing on your screen
oh no we have a church is not push their
button properly so they have to re and
put it before we can bring you all the
scores remember only the middle three or
count towards a total seven point five
and eight do you have a question about
why all the marks are not counted it's
about finding the average so the two
highest and two lowest are discounted to
get the average scores otherwise the
subjectivity plays too much of a part
before the marks count so seven judges
two highs to lows removed and three
count multiplied by the degree of
difficulty QC total before the dive easy
as that straight forward much more
straightforward than doing the dives for
three and a half somersaults with Mike
for corriendo I was very impressed with
Vincent we and oh and next
max Bouchard both of these young
Canadians brothers vitsin certainly
young seventeen-years-old got a bright
future in front of it this is his
easiest die 3.0 certainly starts his
campaign off in pretty steady style I
need six dives six consistently good
dies to be anywhere near the medals
let's see this young man gets on well if
we presume that it will be daily at
Mitchum going head to head
somebody needs to claim the bronze could
easily be Vincent Rando just come out of
World Juniors Meireles 10th in Australia
Maxime Bouchard retired after 2008 World
Juniors in Germany didn't think you
could cut the mustard but it's been
persuaded to come back he said kind of
held together but was sticky tape for
some metal in that body arm stand back
triple somersault with tuck three point
three they'll be different variances of
the arm Stan will see some people like
to do it with a towel some people do not
Maxime is one of those
well my who was because he wasn't meant
to do that
and a little bit of a wobble in the arm
stand balance there lost his balance
manages to hold himself but then when it
goes eventually his take off isn't quite
as strong as it normally is and so as he
exits the die
he thinks he's lower to the water arches
through to try and pull it in but it's
an error and he over rotates it's not
disastrous but it was as strong as I've
seen in training from blacks Emmett
ended an event and a competition of this
quality anything below sevens is not
going to help your middle prospects 6.5
just puts him a little bit behind the
base in round one behind ed good good
saintly act qu UE Vincent Brando and
James Denny only have Lee Dixon but Lee
Dixon obviously and Lee and Dixon
something is diving yet so a new bearing
of Gary Lineker and Lee Dixon on the
board a little chat with the Canadian
coach about something there leo
yeah let's wait and see I don't have any
microphones down there that was the
referee it was a discussion
no idea what was discussed
protests do you need to make protests
straight away that maybe the left we
turned it down we'll find out afterwards
so there's a little disruption now the
competition really starts the
head-to-head Mitchum versus Daley take
two four years ago it was daily there
will it be this evening well I'll try
and do four remember is give you their
marks this morning so you can compare
how they've done to my 81 on the for
three and a half somersaults for Matt
Mitcham this morning oh there you go the
pressure beginning to tell did the delay
caused him to lose concentration because
that is ever for Mitchum his easiest
died and he's fluffed in their door is
wide open you cannot start your campaign
with like a sixty pointer not when
you're taking on Tom Daley what are we
going to see this evening six point five
s is what you see there and that is some
twenty three points down and what he did
this morning it's already a big amount
of ground to make up for the gold
medalist from Beijing 2008 so man
there's four years ago in Delhi and the
winner on the synchro last night we're
done with it bit good so Tom Daley
I'm stand to start slightly different
version of it from what we've seen thus
far
um stand back triple somersault now when
he performed this dive in the
preliminaries this morning seventy three
point five zero just give you a little
heads up the div' has a problem with is
coming next seventy three point five
though boys arm stand back triple this
morning
hello Tom Tali welcome to the men's 10
metre platform final this is a defending
champion that is his first dive and he's
gonna get nine so maybe even some tens
he has capitalized on mitchum leaving
the door open Tom Daley is absolutely
smashed it 90 points plus beautiful tie
game on should we just stop the
competition there 94.5 compared to
seventy three point five what a massive
swing 23 points down mitchum 21 points
up daily swinger 44 points on one dive
from this morning to evening and there
it is you don't even see Matthew bitch
up in the frame there is on page 2
that's good sterling well again for
Australia would say Liang qu he we're
having problems with a photography
problem that we had in London everyone
to get a snapshot of Tom Daly and we
know how affected this diving in London
so the ground just being told to turn
those flashes off Tom Daly has a lead of
8 points already and maybe more
importantly has a lead of some 36 over
Matt Mitcham after round 1 now a little
bit concern for this young man because
we saw in practice tonight the trading
warm up and he wasn't getting anything
right let's hope it gets through his six
unscathed inward three and a half
somersaults with tuck for siddhartha
deshi this is his big dive of the
program at 3.2
well Siddhartha was well he was almost
there all the components where the right
places take off is it's good enough good
jump good extension from the legs moving
or safe distance from the diving board
spots the water just isn't quite
confident enough to straighten out quick
enough he still hits the water a little
bit loose a little bit soft and
therefore won't get more than the marks
coming up five 5.5 s is about right if
he was a bit more confident on the exit
the dive you can get sevens are beads to
see what he does in the remain dives
because when he was doing this morning
taking about 25 30 seconds over each
time but it seemed to be
counterproductive he was trying to get
himself prepared for it seem to be too
much thinking and execution of the dives
who were suffering because of it
14-year old Matt Dixon
well the European juniors now stepping
up to the senior ranks with a reverse
two and a half somersaults with tuck
only two point eight degree of
difficulty so Sims are keeping up with
the others this needs to be very good
for the young man
oh I said tremendous entry into the
water he's just a little bit untidy as
he gets in
I'll talk you through it on the replay
the jump is good only tiny is he 14
years old spots awards and kinks I look
so his toes reaches back just tips his
feet over with him so he got eight Nahas
on this early I think this loan he gets
seven in a heart but he's loving this
fine I did a little bit of a wiggle and
a waddle on the way in so yeah 7.5 s
alright middle of the back in terms of
marks its strength on the board is no
question is strength in terms of getting
the door open to go to the war the
cooldown area might be qu you eat comes
other arm stance different to the one we
saw from Tom Daley this one has a double
somersault one and a half twists
attached to it was his dive done by
would say Niang and by corriendo and
also by Mitchum in this round three
point two degree of difficulty qu e
after round one is in fourth place
nice from to Yui sometimes struggles
with this form the form of this type is
good you looking for legs straight toes
pointed aesthetically pleasing movements
ie
look pretty impress the judges his Pike
shape isn't quite as deep as it needs to
be so he's swinging around looking a
little bit out of control as he squares
up so the judges yeah I'm not sure which
way they're gonna go with it well a
couple well six to seven and a half so
yeah but sure I though they weren't
completes mixed bag of scores luckily
just go match all you're saying earlier
on we do to scan the top ones and the
bottom ones just the middle three will
be included in that score
and for the time being at least with
still queries ago he's leading 139 that
will not last for long probably be
overtaken on this diver though after a
great start this morning don't think
they'd be good have problems with this
second after round one his inward three
and a half somersaults three point two
for the first of the Australians will
see Mitchum being the other
yeah was about good this morning that is
better it can still be improved because
all the hard work the take off is very
very strong squeezing it to the touch
tape completes the dive very easily just
doesn't quite straighten this body out
on the end if he straightens out he
could even get as high as nines because
he's going in slightly rounded shall we
say he's only gonna get that 7.5 gold
medalist with Matt Mitcham last night in
the 10-meter synchro okay trying to add
to his collection but probably the
moment on that form gonna be in the top
three shaker but there's such big
tariffs attached to the dives that come
later which was about three point six is
a lot of them 3.7 s3 men doing the
forward four and a half which is 3.7
this is a miniscule in comparison 3.2
for leaf and yang of New Zealand inward
three and a half one more time in the
tuck position
yep did sir he makes that guy so easily
3.2 is still very very challenging lots
can go wrong you've got to jump away
from the diving board he is a safe
distance yeah Heights out of that very
early but then feels - so he's stuck
and so ducks is chilling it just rolls
over so he won't be getting AIDS he'll
be getting 7s sixty seven point two
seven seven and seven so hard towards a
total if you are new to all this and OH
although those of you been with us all
week probably think we'll we know this
by now but it is the degree of
difficulty multiplied by the scores that
count add up to that total score team
Tom Daley do it
can you see James Deli do it now the arm
stand back triple somersaults putting
sixty seven point two zero for James
Deli silver medal in the platform of
Cinco last night role model is Jenson
Button
nope it stopped here for James Danny
yeah it's good it's good all the way
until the entry so James
steady balance strong push off the hands
flicking the legs squeezing into the
tongue shape and just here Missy goes
into the water just allowing his feet to
tip over with him given the impression
the dive is going over but really just
needed to extend a little bit more
pointless toes back towards the diving
board to stay vertical minor error just
communicates with the coach ATH get
there from the leads diving Club six
point five to that total of sixty four
point three five good ahead of him to
Yui ahead of him and arrive as I follow
at least a bronze melt and he won't be
seeing daily Mitchum was invincible ears
would say Liang of Malaysia see on stand
time right this way no I just as those
bit on the arm stand divers think it's
nothing to speak of I don't see much
mere mortals do find it quite a tricky
thing to watch arm stand back double
somersault one half twists in a free
position third after round one
well Lucy go and leaving the dive
marginally short vertigo though he
enters the water steady our pilot is
great isn't it when you get the camera
to zoom in just to see the concentration
and the effort that goes into these
dives the judges of course do not see
the replay their marks are already in
the computer Bootsy Liang's short
vertical only gonna get sinks and a
half's Wow will that be good enough to
stay in contention at the medals not
likely with Mitchum and Davy still to
come and indeed we know in a very good
start
so although he's third right now that
could easily be sick or possibly seventh
on the end of this round there will be a
lot of fluctuations in position but this
young man very very impressive star is
definitely future star of Canadian dye
me there's no riding McCormick now he's
retired from 10 music I'm down to three
and one so they're looking for a new
start see how that state party in the
past on that 10 and 3 perhaps
here's his heir apparent Vincent flurry
and alt arm stand back double somersault
one and a half twists in the free
position but he goes and dine he goes
that's really really tidy
[Applause]
[Music]
good strong push off the hands pops up
into the air that's really tight his
feet actually come quite close
underneath the tower it needs to be
careful of that it does lose his feet
helicopter feet marginally so it's been
kind of flutter so the judges might if
they spot that penalize one judge has to
judge number three giving him a six the
others ignoring or missing the feet
flutter I like a feet flutter but I
never will
7.5 will count towards the total Maxime
Bouchard was happy to be with us after
the problems he's been through for three
and a half seven sort with pike for the
canadian yes nice tidy straight
up-and-down clean vertical entry into
the water
sweet points zero degree of difficulty
so you know what he sometimes well he's
gonna be in the mix for the bronze and
he's diving very well that's gonna nudge
over 70 points which is great because
it's only 3.0 degree of difficulty 8
across the board you'll see an 8.5 there
but discount that sand because it is
discarded only three marks the ones
without the line through them will add
up okay I'd say I try and tell you what
the team main two divers got this
morning well this was a seventy five
point six for Matthew Mitchell but as we
mentioned spent 23 points swing against
him and Tom Daly got 21 more points on
his opening dive he did this morning so
a big margin to make up already for
Mitchum on his arm stand back double
somersault two and a half twists 99 will
take you into the lead not likely
or is it
it's beautiful our balance he is cranked
the start a little bit too much he
giving too much beans and could not stop
that rotation
it's a tricky dive to do it many times
it's just a real pain because you've got
so many twists to do to get in with a
rotation it's very easy to over rotate
that's exactly what Mitchum's done
he is lagging behind now this could
prove to be critical dropped another 12
from this morning Daly's next dive is
crucial we've used a description before
a few times and he would describe it to
as his bogey dive is the description of
it back two and a half somersaults two
and a half twists in the pike positions
worth three point six degree of
difficulty who's down in 37 s 2030 7.8
that's why was a huge swing to Mitchum
in election terms this compose himself
take a long time over this just look at
the mannerisms and the facial
expressions on this one
oh it's better than this morning it's
better than this morning's they all
struggle with it that is a step in the
right direction it's a step in the right
direction but it's not as good as he did
in Mexico he's not extending his legs
out of the diving board the judges are
going to give him success because he
just anita 11 meets a platform forget to
take off like that he just needs to
extend the legs but the problem is at
the start he's not quite as relaxed as
he needs to be he's watching the replay
there the judges don't see the replay
64y well that's out of the way no time
for more dives if you want the gold it's
yours to take and even though wasn't up
to spec enough to scratch for Daly
it's still a massive swing to him from
Matt Mitcham again 37 this morning 64 in
the evening daily leads from bed good
and to Yui there one two three members
James Denny on the second page as is
Matthew Dixon in 10 and sit up at their
shoes next in 11 o'clock I live here
because he takes longer over this dive
and does Ruffin the dowel over a serve
something like half a minute this
morning so right he's ready to go
stopwatch on
well according to my timekeeper 28
seconds thinking about it but only 1.5
seconds to complete the dive or 1.8 so
back two and a half in the pipe position
this is Hadley very good for the setup
in training he was everywhere suede but
upright in in the time when he counts in
the competition he's nailed it
demand from India lands up by vertical
and good ii won't dive well this morning
it didn't work for him the length of
time he was cogitating but that worked
alright and once he's not gonna be in
the top ten the way things are looking
it's trying to get as many marks as he
can huge cheer for the young man who
really does seem to be relishing a
chance of performing in front of this
audience and the huge audience at home
14 years of age from Plymouth bronze at
the European juniors and British
Championships a year was very close to
400 marks for gymnasts now divert that
dickson arm stand forward double
somersault one twist 3.1 already can see
the strappy on his arm the battering
that I was taking
oh it's a great take officer so composed
so balanced beautiful I understand you
can seize gymnastics background here
this is almost like a vault you to NASA
home you'll notice what needs to go in
to get that forward rotation from a
handstand without having a a springboard
in a vault to get off just faltering on
the edge into the water it cranks it a
little bit too much and it's over he
goes for the time-being into the lead he
goes but as he's only the second one up
that's not gonna last very long but 50
1.15 brilliance immense and not
repeatable in terms of his age
experience for the young man from Leeds
now Hughie or Malaysia they place the
mode nice and solid opening a couple of
round dives
this one will be performed in the Tuck
position three point three it's a great
difficulty we will get up into the 3.6
is very shortly and the three points
Evans Mitchum fish is with two three
point six is dr. Lee has that forward
four and a half worth three point seven
but this is a back three and a half
somersaults for Choo you eat
or what a mess what a shame
faltering as he went into the water
[Applause]
drifting too far away from the diving
board which means that when you come out
of the dive it's difficult to control
and over egos that's our second or third
surfboard moment of this competition
tidal wave
incoming there we go splash moving away
from the diving board judge 3 was Simon
Cowell judge - well sorry in a
completely different way
[Music]
donut bed good master don't mean died
we'd love to repeat that six times
because that's been spot-on for him so
far today this is kind of waste program
just unfolded a little bit in the
prelims Dominic bedgood currently in
second place they're back three and a
half somersaults we're tuck the man who
set a moment putting the pressure on Tom
Daley well that is exactly the same as
to UE he went surfing on the bottom way
over just showing how difficult these
dives are and this is the time you need
to get your surfboards out there's the
wave nobody bet good give us a wave they
just did
threes 3.5 s and Williams look at medals
just now it's gonna have a big
reparation job to do after that deadly
three marks total that's gonna slip him
well down the Becky oh dear one two
three four five six seven more to go
at least we go from second down into
seventh place here must be eight the Fen
yang of New Zealand 3.30 see yeah like
three divers all duis and slightly
different varieties the next two divers
do it in slightly different varieties of
this back three and a half seven sorts
with tuck next diver James Denny will do
it in the pike position oh that's good
from Lee that's how you do it so to Yui
and Dominic but good went surfing and
leave has disappeared without a rip
entry just got his boots on there these
feet are flat and then eventually points
his toes good I cheated the water Martin
Lee short vertical but much much better
it's the best to be back three and a
half's in the tough position we've just
seen three in a row even at this stage
the minor medals are definitely up for
grabs Tom Daley needs to keep the
consistency going for the gold because
he's gonna be untouchable if he does but
silver and bronze not out of the range
of anybody in the top order of the
moment including this young man James
Denny go with the same time we've seen
but in a slightly different form go some
tuck to pike he's next time by the way
there's one that I've seen on YouTube no
splash but it's gonna be very hard for
this to be splash 'less back three and a
half Pike big taraf three point six for
James Denny
well that's what Hitler Tom one of the
dives that used the last night in the
sick crow and James doing the opposite
to what he did in the sinker and the
Sicari went over over a vertical here
he's slightly short in fact he is quite
short Who am I trying to kid he's
landing pretty much on the backs of his
legs going loose in the low back is such
a difficult dive but when it goes wrong
it can go drastically wrong it will drop
down the leaderboard without one well
from Lee everybody else is having
problems with our dive in different
configurations
he blew in James Denny 48.6 and more and
more it's looking like it's not gonna be
as much pressure as we thought on Tom
Daley but certainly Aang was there are
they're about but he had a four-second
Ryan dive so he needs to get it back on
track with a four three and a half
the pike that is back on track is very
good for mood Sealy I his easiest dive
3.0 forward three and a half in the pike
position such as strong athlete leaps
off the diving board
she asked rolling into the water he's
gonna get eight so that that'll help him
release will he see himself top of the
leaderboards yes time being he will
first to go over the 200 mark 208 to be
a precise nine clear of Lee and
seventeen ahead of bedgood the main
movers and shakers are about to perform
[Music]
at the halfway stage approaching future
of Canadian male 10 meter diving has
arrived in Edinburgh let's see whether
he accepts that tag gratefully and
gladly on this reverse three and a half
somersaults we're tuck three point four
attached to this nice taking it on yep
the Canadians both of them go fits in
and makes him to follow shortly Wow good
dives this one in particular three point
four it's tricky get it all the way
round anything above 70 points is good
75 points even better then up into the
higher echelon as we go I would not be
at all surprised of this young man isn't
on the podium later on today started
with great confidence so the great smart
rally with a great attitude it might
well be a battle between the Canadians
for medals here or is it good not very
Matt Mitchum's night and that's two of
them good to sneak on to the medal
podium seam Bouchard it's not too far
shy of a top three place in fact where
everybody else faltering so able to step
up on that 3.4 say we have some big
tariff dives together if it gets more
immense as the competition goes on this
is mid-range really not for Bouchard
though reversed three and a half
somersaults with tuck for the second
while the Canadians
guys an unusual technique he's balanced
he got his tiptoes and he's standing
forwards that's highly unusual II took
ages to go as well it's exactly the same
dive as his teammate Vinson has just
performed it it's not as good so that
means that max will drop a little bit
further away from where he was on the
previous rounds he only needed seven and
a half stakes but that's only gonna get
5.5 24 points behind his teammate now
the three rounds to go that can be made
up Lando is setting the pace and once
the well looked like being lesser
medalist now round three Smalling was a
very good dive for Matt Mitcham on his
reverser II and a half that's his best
dive of the competition 88.4 he got that
he's down on his first two dives tonight
it's a good time for Mitchum he manages
to keep the splash time it is the RIP
entry that we're looking for he does
wash over vertical so he's only gonna
get well 18 hearts maybe you needed to
be completely bolt upright to get 9 in
Hoss and tens which is pretty much what
he would need to put pressure on Tom's
daily this is a big big dive Oh 85
points plus well he got 450 total this
morning it's a fatal jig of the joy and
delight for Matt Mitcham well because
come close to emulated what he did this
morning still hasn't quite done it
they've two attempts of tariffs the
weakest dive for Tom Daley doesn't
always translate into our execution it
will be though any moment now an inward
three and a half somersaults with tuck
for daily take off his electric he's
been working so hard on this boom on the
start really good strong start rolling
over as he goes into the water he's
going to get eight and a half probably
not good enough for a night good enough
though he'll be over 80 points six and
he knows in his head how that compares
with this morning not that favorably any
one point six believe three points this
morning so first time on is evening
performance he's down on March birds
only marginal Tom Daly Vincent the we
end up Mitchum was woken up and come to
the party now in third place I would say
Liang in fourth and the two other
Englishmen in the field James Denny in
eighth and Matt Dixon in tenth
so we've reached halfway it's looking
good for Tom Daley worth 26 point gap
between him and the rest right now but
we are only halfway as I mentioned the
big dives for the likes of Siddappa
deshi but the main divers still to come
okay between eight seconds last time
it's enough possession how long will you
take over this one reverse two and a
half somersaults with pike still not
quite ready to go
so what your TV hasn't frozen it's
actually happening
well next to me in the radio section
Karen Pickering is summed up perfectly
she shifted back in a chair and held
herself because it doesn't take or hit
in the water but over 35 miles now and
when you don't get anywhere near up by
that B does hurt you can tell why sit
Upton was taking his time and having to
think about it
it's a tricky die for verse 2 and 1/2 in
the pike position and he's just had the
rough of the water this man made a steel
or while he was doing something similar
in the build-up and the training before
the event itself and just took the
knocks got back on that 10 meter board
did it all over again but his brain went
from the practice I'm afraid Matt Dixon
is not to put off by that 3.24 of the
young step his senior debut at the core
of games in with three and a half
somersaults 3.2 he's probably safe from
finishing bottom let's see if you can
make a few strides up with this
- the 14-yard from Plymouth
he's absolutely smashed it
Wow that is what he's capable
Oh they've got a big scores coming his
way I am liking that good work Matty
Dixon well physically he might look out
of place here for those marks on 8.5 8.5
April for 81.6 my oh my I just say he's
over the fish bottom he may well be a
couple of places above that the
performances of that kind that is
sensational from the oh man and just
shows the promise he has done employers
and Ebanks working so hard with him and
the others great little program and he
of course worked for 12 years with the
Tom Daley before he moved to London
that's what special coaches do chew you
eat in with three and a half somersaults
were tuck 3.24 the Malaysian wrong into
the field in night at the moment boys
better come to you eat yeah he's third
right time to back trade half but he
went surfing cost him his spot on the
leaderboard this is better not as good
as Matty Dixon but not far off
strong takeoff choosing to use a towel
as a comfort thing to non-slip surface
on the platform and sometimes prefer the
grip of a towel which is the blue towel
that you saw on the 10 meter they're
just as gue was performing his dive
seventy six point eight zero doesn't
look to me like he's doing pushing for a
medal stay with big tariff times which
can easily be dropped or failed on
occasion can't always made a prediction
even at this stage but there were two
rounds to go
looks like he's not gonna be in the
shake up this man still could be getting
a bit too in and out great start in both
the prelims and the final for Dominic
that's good three point for reverse
three and a half sixty will put him
above qu you'ii be looking though for a
tease if he can
I sped up from bed goods better for bed
good
this went awry in the prelims you almost
gets it right here in the final just
needs to look back a little bit more
marginally short vertical as it goes in
it's still a good dive way over 70
points where will that put him seventy
six point five is what he gets in terms
of total marks and for the time being
lead keeps changing hands and it always
says at this stage as I was just get
their noses in front of the opposition
but we're not down to the sharp ends by
any means yet seven divers to go and if
Lee James Denny will be performing that
dive reverse three and a half
somersaults we're tucked three point for
the looking to go crashing through the
200 barrier here currently in fifth
place so again not too far shy of a top
three place yes he is it just goes to
show how difficult these dives are this
one in particular the reverse three and
a half you've got to jump away from the
diving board spin backwards towards it
which is exactly what he does he's just
squeezed his shape and there comes out
if he's diving a little bit too early
lands flat on his back what a shame
yeah it looks like his chance of a medal
which look very good before that dive
have just evaporated the Royal can walk
all in Emperor
former Chinese diver retired came back
coaching in Wellington Nicky is still
coaching as well as well as performing
but my person who decided retirement was
not for him consideration retirement for
this man 20 years of age course 12 days
been around a long time so both about
the same age we haven't seen anywhere
near as much of James Danny the syncro
were Tom Daly last night here he is on
the individual with the reverse three
and a half the tuck you saw how it went
last time let's see how it goes this
time can he improve and we've just seen
from the fengyang oh yes he can
that's much better James jumps quite far
from the diving port of a shinobi
working hard with a deep up in Leeds
high-performance diving Center on this
doesn't really need to be that far away
from the diving board makes it tricky to
control but he does a good job on that
so just throwing up too much splash as
he goes in that's much better than this
morning a better than the synchro
competition last night progress and
that's what they're looking for
still not quite where it's totally
likely to be on deep where he wants it
to be but six point five and seven means
he's above a few doing fengyang leaned
out and three points clear of Matt Dixon
it's a liang sometime is faltering at
the moment they're not quite getting
there top scorers he's in range on a
medal already got the three meter let's
just go through the card one meter three
meter and 2 meter and here's his back
three and a half
send him towards 300 points if he gets
it right oh I thought he was out way too
early on
but he knows exactly where he is good
every unawareness do you know where you
are when he's spinning around and
falling down towards the Earth at
breakneck speeds blow yes is the answer
from Bootsy Liang that's good he was a
little bit early but Manisha Stern's
bullet mines yeah looking back up to the
hole he just created it he can punch
through the walls with his hands in a
graph position getting feedback from his
coach himself an exceptional diver in
his day used to dive against me he's a
bit slimmer than though not as handsome
obviously I'll do Vincent DeLorean doll
I've never known you speechless before
3.2 degree of difficulty now this young
Canadian 17 years of age back at what
he's done so far diving in the Canadian
program for what now 12 years very
experienced but not at this level yet oh
it's a good dog just a little bit of
smash couldn't quite keep keep the
splash down it started a rip entry where
you punch a hole in the water by
grabbing the hands it look to show he's
going to disappear
just as you see here Liberty smash being
thrown up it's a good dive it'll get
eight and that certainly keeps his
campaign for a metal alive keep saying
it oh I'm not going to put the mockers
on him and Lux his consistency
I like his attitude you know like the
way it's performing tonight excellent
dive eights across the board takes him
above boots a liang chances are he'll be
in medal position at the end of this
round if that's he definitely well
because Maxine Bouchard could not
overtake him at this stage best he can
do is second place and to do that it's
basically to get tense and we've not
seen too many of those well there mr.
Daly might have something to say about
that when he steps up shortly
yeah it's good he kept all the splash
down little bit soft in his lower back
as it goes into the water so max looking
to pick up on a slightly faltering dive
in the previous round and that will help
they'll only be in the early 70s so 72
73 with that one if you get 7 point 5 s
& 8
pick up me calculations to sixty four
point four seven point five and eight
look out towards his total
[Music]
around 4:00 this morning Matt Mitcham 60
7.20
which actually was his second lowest
score his lowest coming on round 5 this
is where it starts swing one stage Tom
Daly was last in the prelims this
morning Mitchum was leading the way for
quite a while
inward three and a half somersaults with
tuck three point two for the 2008
Olympic champion he is not having a very
good meet at all mitchum it's not on
fire in fact he's not even smoldering
this is very very weak from the 2008
olympic champion
he's been smashing it in trading and he
just isn't he has to find his groove Wow
so he's going to be battling for you
know to hold on to his potential silver
here you can see nobody's smiling happy
yeah that's for the force wave and a
smile isn't it well he's happy it's a
jazz hands but look at the jazz hands
there because that's emulating what he
did this morning and that chasm between
him and Tom Daly opens up thoughts but
this we're talking about the big one
being his second round I once his bogey
dive which he did okay on but this this
morning he set into the stratosphere 101
point seven five twice he went over a
hundred this morning and consecutive
dives this was the first of them you
wait for the roof to come off here so
listed building so hopefully it doesn't
forward four and a half some sorts with
tuck go tom ice not as good as this
morning but is plenty good enough for
him to stay in the lead three point
seven degree of difficulty forward four
and a half somersaults in the tough
position
Tom way T Pike side he's got a great
takeoff on that as we saw this morning
he sailed over 100 points this will be
close to 80 maybe just over 80 points
but you know what there is a really
competition going on the moment tom is
way out in front
Mitch I'm not really featuring and
that's in the top three is he he's art
and Tom Daly been like Jack law and the
prelims of three meter is miles and of
everybody else and this is the final
when it counts three twenty point four
five look at that nearly thirty mark
separating here man Vincent Dorian dole
would say Liang Matt Mitcham just
holding onto the coattails of the medals
not in there yet
James Denny innate antics midnight and
sit up but there xi and xi for india
looking good for Tom Daley keep very
good indeed
went to anoint him yet with that gold
medal this is too big died for Matthew
Mitchum including his last one when she
got eighty six on the boys he got some
ground to make up
our deshi forward to an hour somersaults
one twist
that is the best dive we've seen from
pardeshi certainly on this guy sometimes
has a bit of trouble with his twist
wobbles around for this one he manages
his feet are quite pointed are they
they've got one pointed at one half
pointed crossed over a little bit so
he's a little bit rough around the edges
knees straight up and down
he's hold his triceps a saying that he
said a bit of pain I'm not in the least
bit surprised having seen what he put
himself through today not to talk about
the competition this morning and tonight
will release done in between times
basically kept getting back on that 10
meter board and doing it and he got it
right it's not very surprising his body
is time to break down a little bit it
could be earlier in the week as well
it's round I've Matt Dixon is acquitting
himself very very well indeed the 14
year old from Plymouth British champion
this year
maybe they got 400 marks and not at
school either back three and a half
somersaults with tuck three point three
or the Devonian
oh nice just a little over rotation too
big died for him three point three
starting backwards swinging the arms
above the head looking at where you've
been not where you're going kicking his
feet up towards the 10-meter just a
little bit too high throwing a bit of
splasher that's still that's probably
better than he did this morning let me
just check yes he only got fives on this
this morning that'll be six point five s
good work buddy do good work in deme a
TD oh you're simon against the Gold
Coast in the filled out a bit you look
grown a bit they look a completely
different competitor but fantastic spear
has so many in Delhi who come back and
improved on their performances for years
on qu e seventh place well I've got say
three four five and six are very tightly
bunched so needs to jump out of the pack
it's not too far back with two rounds to
go it's three point four reversed three
and a half somersaults we tuck for
Hughie
oh you're my goodness oh now that is
like being smacked around the back of
the head
by a baseball bat ouch
so it's all okay until now he doesn't
quite get its hands back at all just
collapse into the water that water can
feel like your arms are being ripped out
from the sockets in fact I had for
reconstructive shoulder surgeries in my
career diving from the 10-meter I hope
you eat doesn't need to book himself in
for one
well his body folded up like one of your
deck chairs there as he went into the
water
Nicky kind of for half his body meant
the other half of his body going in
there I think as few people are just
recoiled it's like watching Doctor Who
when you're a young kid you're behind
the sofa after that here donate bed good
of Australia now who wants to get into
these medal positions we're not assuming
tom days well it just yet but we are
looking at those who might push for
silver and bronze he's fifth and this is
the big one you saw Daly do pretty well
on recently honey three men are doing it
Ford four and a half oh that's good for
bed goods that's okay little bit of
splash being thrown up
so needs to squeeze interest up shape a
little bit Boise loosen it but he's a
little scrappy but he gets it on his
head
it is 3.7 so it's worth a lot because
mathematically the scores multiplied by
the degree of difficulty
okay 68 well then for that splash if we
look at the 80s but 68.4 well sure I bet
you think your home that looks really
good but that's why she kind of gives it
away a little bit but you guys go into
the lead with Lee Danny same yang Rando
Bouchard Mitchum and of course our
runaway leader at the moment Tom Daly to
come back to the arm stance I don't see
one of these for a while
I'm stand back a double somersault one
and a half twists he's off he's off but
he's in and he disappears he everything
he needs in the dive good strong take
off one and a half twist double
somersault and a good entry into the
water
no I wasn't quite ready for that
commentary but I got it out in the end
hopefully it made sense why James have
over lifetime
sevens 67 for Li fen yang yeah I don't
think we're gonna see him on the medal
podium later on
sevens was okay to be honest when it
seemed totally under control with that
not holding back the senior English
divers here a year three point three non
serves only a three point zero zero to
three point six or Saroyan the next and
see what happens
James Denny has done just that and the
courses this was spot on
eighth place can be translated into
something much much better back two and
a half two and a half twists you've seen
this before
it's a Tom Daley's earlier dive that
that she was okay today
oh it's good font any three point six
two and a half somersault two and a half
twist in the pike position great stroke
takeoff good leg extension helicopter
feet so the judges all cane him for that
this could have got eights maybe even an
eight point five pretty gotta keep your
legs together your toes pointed you
can't be flipping your feet around like
they're helicopter rotors ooh
Denny Ruby do seven point five and a
seven for the Englishman from reads 20
years of age same age as Tom Daley but
he said it's a second of the most tips
and leigh below him that was still not
quite he can be that same yang is kind
of profiting from other people around
him not doing what they should do so
that's why he finds himself in third but
so canadians gonna have something to say
about that and Matt Mitcham forty
eventually to reverse three and a half
or just just just manages to hang on to
that we watching min training
and he's been a little bit here and
there that is short short of vertical
but it's tight it's good form and so
he's probably gonna sneak sevens from
the judges that'll keep him in
contention for a medal Bootsy Liang one
dies to go it's on together calculators
out it's gonna get very tight because
those chasing Daly
grouped together very close here though
as a 19 point advantage for who'd say
Liang over bed good 7s cross the board
71 point for bin sent way and all so he
pointed out to me that does that mean no
water or worse than that effect in in
French which doesn't seem quite right
for a diver is it this is three point
three no he is second place at the
moment
well that's good well what's that gonna
do is that gonna help or hinder so it's
okay it's above average it's a big dive
so I'm gonna see a couple of these in a
row now this one from Vincent Max is
gonna follow the dementia was
diagramming his back for enough Pike to
a back thrown off targets so this is
only gonna get sevens which means you'll
be less than 70 points Willie bunch up
with oopsie Liang I think you well yes
precisely what he has done
two and a half point lead over the
Malaysian and that is nothing going into
the last round of Tolerance certainly no
lead you can protect that see what
Bouchard might just have fallen away
from a medal push well you know though
he gets 90 he goes in behind this
Canadian colleague on this back three
and a half somersaults with tuck exactly
the same dive you've just seen he's done
well he's just a little bit low on the
water losing it on the takeoff not quite
powerful enough not generating enough
spitting speed so it needs to get his
arms to and extend a little bit more
through the legs so as you can see here
just arching as he gets in it's clean
and tidy but he will drift now away from
the medals yeah I think he's got too
much to make up now he is 25.5 18 yang
28 points behind his teammate so not
today for men or for Maxime Bouchard
continuing with giving you a little
heads-up on this morning's performance
compared to tonight this was actually
Matthew Mitchell's worse time in terms
of marks worth mention he's changed it
so he's gone from a two point six degree
of difficulty about three and half Pike
to this a back three and a half
somersaults in the tucked position three
point three yeah fifty two point two he
picked up this morning that's what he
does now yeah it much better but then it
was this morning obviously it's a
different died he's playing safe I think
he's left himself too much to do to
challenge Tom for the gold but he's
happy to fight for this silver will that
be enough to get him closer to the
Canadian and to the Malaysian it's okay
but it's not good enough I've seen him
to go straight tens on this dive he's
short vertical there he's gonna struggle
to get a medal that would be a turn up
for the books wouldn't adjust third at
the moment where Davy still to come so
high and OH
and who'd say Liang likely medalists
right now the star turn the class act
tonight so often we have seen him beep
the world champion from Rome 2009 bronze
medalist from London 2012 Thomas Robert
Daly back three of the half somersaults
with Mike one of those high tariffs
dives got over a hundred on this this
morning
toys recordable turns turns turns bye
come on judges you might as well that is
perfect so this is textbook this is Tom
Daly pretty much diving for the cold if
the churches don't give it a turn
wow I think that they're wrong this is
perfection hundred points here we come
let's you just join these friendly come
dancing judging ballet from alamos seat
in the stratosphere Leon Taylor as if he
was Tom Daly well sadly those tens or
that's ten does not count towards a
title and the total nine point five nine
point five and nine point five two so
Daly looks like it's going to go over
500 for 23:05 incidentally endo in
second look outside it is though for the
next two places and Matt Mitcham has a
big dive at the end three point six
Denny in seven matthew dixon in eight so
you'd noticed Tom Daly walking up the
steps there followed by his coach Jen
there's been lots of questions where is
he going he's actually moving up you're
moving yourself up to the dry land dive
the area where he'll prepare for the
next die there's crash mats out there
he'll be preparing for each and every
dive we enjoyed having him here I think
it's enjoy being here those body may not
feel quite that way after this
competition sin alpha deshi leaves his
arm stands till the very end to point
seven so it's not a big tariff die but I
feel the creaking joints as he gets into
the upright position always off yeah
these are fee wants to get this
competition done
[Applause]
and he has so that's six dives he has
hurt himself though I'm quite a few of
his dives in training but he is made of
tough stuff that's it he can have a vest
a beautiful dive to finish extranet into
the water doesn't really hold his arms
that long enough so the judges will
penalize him he got 17 feet out his arm
stand well done
Sid asked bonus you 250 8.30 keeps away
fear thank you to Indian divers here
he's gonna need pushes all the way back
on that flames to support his aching
body huge cheer once again for the
little man they look very different in
four years time is Matthew Dickson you
imagine being 14 being pint-sized and
doing a forward two and a half
somersaults with one twist that's a view
the Matthew Dixon hairs and what he's
about to do it's really gone for it
he's naive as he landed on the head to
the 10-meter board have my headphones
off me but going he pushed so much
effort into it pops up into the air just
a little bit of an overvote ation one
twist into the two and a half somersault
just drifting over a vertical water
performance from this young boy three
six six
[Applause]
[Music]
yeah we'll see more of him
European chaps sure he's going at the
world champs ex year and the Olympics in
Rio almost certain to be part of the GB
team lot can change in two years of
diving though injuries and illness and
stuff like that but I think they'll see
him competing in Rio in a couple of
years time a lot of promise shown by
this young man as well but hasn't quite
been realized this evening final round
for qu e 3.2 in the pike position of
back two and a half somersaults one and
a half twists this is how he finishes
off a very arduous week edges are a lot
of diving
yeah it's a tidy finish from gue two and
a half some sauce with one and a half
twists only three point two degree of
difficulty the next diver humbly beg
good we'll add a twist to this time
making the even more complex and earning
an extra point four degree of difficulty
so this is good fun to you II just
rolling over he's had a pretty steady
performance today we'll finish outside
of the medals but he's dived in out to
every competition available and he's do
reversed and now he can 7.57 sixty eight
point eight I'm just gonna finish below
Matthew Dixon it's all make bed good
kind of top and tail in terms of his
best performances from this morning
great opening of a bad finish fifth
place and what's you need to get up
there and really needs mid 80s high
eighties preferably on the sixth three
point six back two and a half two and a
half twist it gets 90 or so good push
for a medal
yeah he's a good twister didn't quite
finish the dive off its landing very
similar to Tom but for different reasons
so tonics takeoff is good twist very
very quickly just Easter squeezes and
pike shape a little bit longer to
straighten out as he goes in it's high
risk high degree of difficulty didn't
quite work out for the young Australian
no there's a good start I could finish
this morning not a good finish in the
evening as well he's a bit down on his
total mark doesn't make 400 this time
round United seven five five and there
is metal chances disappeared
[Music]
Lee Korean dough Bouchard Mitchum all
doing this dive in the last round my
place for we coach from Wellington and
decided after retiring a few years ago
he's gonna come back into the sport and
has done just that god it's a beautiful
time to finish family he's done a lot of
diving as well great vertical entry to
the water
hardly any splash here's one and a half
twist two and a half somersaults moving
away from the diving board a little bit
I think that's a good entry maybe even
get some eights from the judges
it's a couple of faults was early in his
program so you won't break 400
back up about 20 points shy just over
yes of course
okay James Eddie what can you do for us
on your biggest dive only three men are
doing this James Denny is doing it Tom
Daly did it now I need some 95 couldn't
get eight and a half nearly nine to go
top is he capable of that
twenty-year-old completes we put it past
it
nice okay it's pretty good you did an
absolute beauty next to Tom yesterday
this is the dive they've got the way out
of right out of trouble really they were
way off the pace in the synchro both he
and Tom just not quite straightening out
into the water there you can see you
probably get six nails from the judges
just straighten out a little bit more
bit less splash he'd have been eight and
that would have been a huge score so
just under 400 total reviewing it going
over it with his coach I don't see
nothing much could be done about it this
time but when they get back on that send
me the platform again and ad will know
how to resolve that problem the problem
is say Liang Malaysia to look at the
rankings he's there in third place
doesn't seem to have shifted from that
third place the last few rounds so
what's it gonna take to get him in first
place well in this three point two
inward three and a half sixty-eight just
over a seven average we'll get him at
the top of the board with four more to
go so beautiful booty Liang is that
going to be good enough for the quads he
won the gold in the three meter
individual B teach at law most himmat
many people's surprise
he's been diving out of his skin he has
saved his best to last to do very well
in the prelims on this Wow this will be
close the pressures on will that be good
enough for silver though mitchum still
to dive all victims got a big dive green
dough has a big dive Daly will have very
little to do just complete the dive
that's pretty much his gold medal you
won't be thinking about those
now 75 will corriendo in the lead so
eights here
the Canadian I think is good as as a
medal he'll be aware of that you're
taking just a little bit more time over
this one very smooth very precise grade
entry that's all he can do is three
point two needs to make it count
so to beat you - si Lang you need to
eights will that be good enough it's
gonna be pretty tight I don't know a
little bit short the vertical as he goes
into the water great list of dives from
the canadian only 17 years old yeah yeah
you will be back I think we are seeing
something is gonna grow in every respect
in terms of his quality I think we'll
see a more bulk top render next time in
corn wealth games competition
Maksym Bashar's basically these tens if
it's gonna get into third place and
obviously daily still to come mitchum
still to come so middle will pass Maxime
Bouchard by today so top want to finish
on to even though the terrace not very
high three point two back two and a half
and one and a half twists I've seen it a
few times before yeah a little bit off
the pace
yeah Holdings elbow then just shows you
how much these divers have to ensure
hitting the water in 35 miles an hour
plus every time just so Piper so hard on
the body how does the brains well my toe
against mister at night isn't it seven
and seven point five for Maxime at
Bouchard all right now we are down to
the last two and that this was worth
eighty six point four Smalley for
Matthew Mitchum it does that now he will
get to the silver medal he does anything
under eighty two it's the bronze medal
so a fluctuation of five points would
make a lot of difference here same died
but this time in the pike position which
means it's a three point six rather than
three point two yeah it's the back two
and a half somersaults two and a half
twist that's where the extra point for
comes fun I don't think that's good
enough for the silver I think that
lonely be good enough just for the
pradhans but let's see his three point
six he's left himself a build it too
much to do maybe that won't even get a
medal let's have a look at this
two and a half twist turn half summer so
she's thrown up too much splash if he
doesn't get more than sevens he's not in
the medals water turn up for the books
is not the 2008 go medicine Beijing and
the silver medalists from four years ago
it's had
a difficult four years since India just
well-documented his book he's back a
report this morning he might be back to
his best he isn't he's not gonna get a
medal this is a demonstration dive now
for Tom Daly because he needs 10 points
he won't be seen like that they wanna go
out with a flourish she wants to get
over 500 marks that's his territory
that's his domain and this is the final
dive for Tom Daly for gold at the
Commonwealth Games they go standing from
Tom Daley retaining his Commonwealth
Games title he won four years ago in
Delhi here he is he carried Glasgow
winning by an absolute country mile
he'll go way over 500 points 90 plus for
this one even with the challenges added
the pre lien the questions about what
he's been doing he silenced his critics
gold for daily well I just surround up
the numbers two nines and a 9.5 to count
towards the total as his new coach from
London
well Tom Daly has done that with
absolute precision he is not that
anybody gets within touching distance or
him
massive chasm between one and two just
look at this some tell you exactly what
you need to know 516 55 for daily and
then the others were scrapping for
second and third scrapping best for
silver good see Liang to add to his gold
from 3 meter and Vincent debris and dole
Oh Canada picking up the bronze Matthew
Dixon
watch out may have been four years time
in the ninth place
[Music]
and gentlemen please take your seats to
make sure you give up a warm welcome to
our medley switches and so without
noting a very soon
[Music]
the medals go through they take 15 SEC's
anyway
and this waxed
and I think about all that about three
days
but science is
[Music]
people directly to the next agents we
are absolutely beautiful I think
so I crossed out so today heritage
in fact the accuracy
[Music]
[Applause]
my chief communications officer must get
[Music]
[Applause]
accompanied by a new competition manager
[Music]
[Applause]
England
[Music]
[Applause]
Oh
[Music]
[Applause]
when the school 7.25 representing
Australia
[Applause]
[Music]
ladies and gentlemen the national anthem
of Australia
[Music]
[Applause]
be presenting right
[Music]
[Applause]
my secretary-general
[Music]
[Applause]
welcome in the first are many metals
international level Conwell games for
the seventeen-year-old
from Quebec Vincent a Hellion . 420 9.25
beating likes of Matthew Mitchum maxxium
Bouchard it's a fourth and fifth and
there's a big smile to accompany that
bronze medal pretty much in the top
three all the way through and finally
made a step up to second in the end by
about four points four and a half points
being more precise boots a liang that's
a silver medal in the ten meter to the
gold in the three meter could work for
him and a good week for him but with
marks of 94 64 hello 81 79 hundred and
two point six and ninety three point
five zero
it was in the competition it was a
procession the Tom Daley
he's gonna win a gold medal more easily
than that in its actual competition so
not to do it
auto pilot and terrific really terrific
we could not have been tried then you
say there's too much stuff outside the
poll well that's the perfect answer for
you
five hundred sixteen point five five so
it is gold once again for Tom Daley
[Music]
[Applause]
the Olympic bronze medalist is the
10-meter platform champion for the
second time round the cold war games
backing up what he did in Delhi in 2010
2014 a repeated even bigger margin this
time and not over Matthew Mitchum / hood
say Liang and Vince at window of gather
with the bronze
[Music]
[Applause]
yeah
[Music]
thank you for being part of these days
you